A Guide to the Shover family Papers, 1787-1857
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Shover family Papers, 1787-1857
Library of Virginia
25157
1.15 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Historical Society of Montana, 28 April 1960.
Biographical/Historical Information
Adam (1744-1816) and Simon Shover (1745-1821) of Loudoun County, Virginia, were the children of Johann and Barbara Shover. Adam was married to Magdelena (Sanbower) Shover (1752-1832). George Shover, Sr. (d. ca. 1835) was married to Elizabeth Bauchman and his son, George Shover, Jr., was married to Suzanne Sanbower, the daughter of Anna and John Sanbower.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1787-1857, including correspondence, accounts and receipts, promissory notes, military records, daybooks, ledgers, legal materials, contracts, and subpoenas of the Shover family of Loudoun County, Virginia; Illinois, Iowa and Ohio. The papers chronicle the lives of several generations of Shover family members and are arranged into three groups: Adam Shover (1744-1816), George Shover, and Simon Shover (1745- 1821). The largest quantity of papers relate to George Shover and date from 1787 to 1857. It is unlikely that the papers related to one specific person, but rather to two or three generations of Shover family members named George. Most likely the papers from Virginia relate to George Shover, Sr. (d. ca. 1835), while the papers from Illinois, Iowa and Ohio relate to George Shover, Jr. Since it was impossible to distinguish the generations with certainty, the George Shover(s) materials were grouped into one.
The papers from the estate of Adam Shover, dated 1789-1825, consist of estate inventories, receipts, agreements, a fire insurance policy from Mutual Assurance Society of Virginia, and grants for land in Loudoun County, Virginia. Also of note are estate auction notices and an account of slaves belonging to Adam Shover. Most of the papers also concern Simon Shover, the administrator of Adam's estate.
The papers of George Shover include financial materials, military records, contracts, correspondence, subpoenas, and daybooks. The bulk of the papers consist of financial materials and include accounts, promissory notes, and receipts. These materials relate to the many business' operated by George Shover in Loudoun County, including a carding and grist mill, farm, and distillery. Of note are the account books, daybooks, and ledgers which recorded the daily activities and finances of these business endeavors.
Beginning in 1830, the focus of the George Shover papers switches to Illinois; Iowa; and Carroll and Jefferson Counties, Ohio. Included are teaching contracts and an school exercise book from Carroll and Jefferson Counties, Ohio; a job contract in Iowa; and a personal account ledger from Illinois, 1840.
The papers from the estate of Simon Shover consist of accounts, correspondence, estate inventories, military records, promissory notes, ledgers, legal materials, and receipts. The military records include an appointment of Simon Shover as captain of the 56th Virginia Regiment, 1st Battalion, in 1795, and a roster of company members. Also of note are the legal materials including deeds, contracts, and receipts for court fees paid in Loudoun County, Virginia, 1819-1822. Most of the papers also concern George Shover, the administrator of Simon Shover's estate.
Arrangement
Arranged in three groups: I. Adam Shover (Estate of). II. George Shover. III. Simon Shover (Estate of).
Contents List
- Shover, Adam, (Estate of), 1789-1825 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Shover, George, Accounts, 1819-1821 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Shover, George, Accounts, 1822-1823 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Shover, George, Accounts, 1824-1837 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Shover, George, Accounts, nd (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Shover, George, Circulars, 1836-1837 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Shover, George, Contacts and agreements, 1818-1854 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Shover, George, Correspondence, 1820-1838 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Shover, George, Daybook, 1821-1822 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Shover, George, Ledgers, 1820-1822 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Shover, George, Ledgers, 1821-1823 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Shover, George, Ledgers, 1830-1843 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Shover, George, Military records, 1820-1828 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Shover, George, Miscellaneous, 1787-1837 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Shover, George, Promissory notes, 1819-1839 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Shover, George, Receipts, 1817-1822 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Shover, George, Receipts, 1823-1824 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Shover, George, Receipts, 1825-1844 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Shover, George, Schoolbook, 1834 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Shover, George, Sheriff sale notices, 1823-1828 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Shover, George, Subpoenas, 1822-1828 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Accounts, 1810-1828 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Auction notices, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Correspondence, 1820-1827 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Estate inventories, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Ledgers, 1813-1822 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Legal materials, 1817-1829 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Military records, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Miscellaneous, nd (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Promissory notes, 1791-1826 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Shover, Simon (Estate of), Receipts, 1817-1829 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Oversized, Ephemera, Shover, George, Account book, 1821-1827 (Box 3)
- Oversized, Ephemera, Shover, George, Account book, 1825-1826 (Box 3)
- Oversized, Ephemera, Shover, George, daybook, 1825-1826 (Box 3)
- Oversized, Ephemera, Shover, George, Ledger, 1827-1857 (Box 3)